A racing second hand, a shining comet!
عقرب دقائق مسرِع، مذنّب لامع
Conan's logic is good medicine for hearts tired by modern society!
استنتاجات كونان دواء ممتاز للقلوب !المُثقلة بالمجتمع الحديث
The old guy goes on a date today! All kinds of ripples are made!
!يذهب العمّ في موعد عاطفيّ اليوم! تُستحدث مختلف الموجات
He sees the single truth for what it is,
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
يحمل مظهر طفل، لكنّ عقله عقل بالغ
His name? Detective Conan!
!اسمه المتحرّي كونان
Yum!
!لذيذة
Ordering pizza was a good idea!
!طلب البيتزا كان خياراً صائباً
That's for sure! We can't eat dinners like this when Dad's around!
بالفعل، لا يمكننا تناول عشاء كهذا عندما يكون أبي موجوداً
He sure knows how to be careless, though! He forgot everything!
إنّه مهمل بحقّ، نسي كلّ أغراضه
He must've been really happy.
لا بدّ أنّه كان بغاية السرور
It's been ten years since he's seen his friend, right?
فقد مضت 10 أعوام مُذ رأى صديقه، صحيح؟
Yeah. He said he was going to drink like crazy,
أجل، قال أنّه سيشرب بكثرة الليلة
so he'll be back late tonight.
ويرجع في وقتٍ متأخّر
I'm really sorry!
!آسفٌ حقّاً
Yeesh! What bad timing!
يا إلهي، يا للتوقيت السيّئ
But I guess it is a company emergency.
لكن ربما ليس باليد الحيلة بما أنّها حالة طارئة في الشركة
We can get together another time soon. Bye!
سأحدّد موعداً لنجتمع مجدداً قريباً، إلى اللقاء
Train ♪2 on the Toto Loop Line will be arriving momentarily.
سيصل القطار الثاني على خطّ حلقة توتو قريباً
Please stand behind the yellow line for your safety.
انتظروا وراء الخطّ الأصفر لسلامتكم رجاءً
It's still only 7:30?
لا تزال السابعة والنصف فقط؟
I should've gone somewhere for more drinks.
كان عليّ الذهاب لمكانٍ آخر للشرب أكثر
Six stops until Beika Station...
...ستّ محطّات حتّى محطّة بيكا
Beika
بيكا
"Beika"...
...بيكا
Just a second!
!انتظر
That was close. I almost missed my stop.
كان ذلك وشيكاً، كدت أتجاوز محطّتي
Candy?
حلوى؟
Was I eating this before?
أكنتُ آكلها؟
What a poetic sight!
يا للمشهد الشاعريّ
It's me, Mori! Mori Kogoro!
!أنا موري! موري كوغورو
Remember? We've met in the Poirot shop below my office!
أتذكرين؟ التقينا عدّة مرّات !في مقهى بوارو أسفل مكتبي
Oh, the great detective, Mori Kogoro-san!
(شيمامورا ساتشيكو (31 مديرة شركة استيراد
Yes! Come to think of it, isn't your apartment building near here?
أجل! بالمناسبة، كان مجمع الشقق الخاص بك بالجوار هنا، صحيح؟
8:00?
الثامنة؟
Whoops! I forgot my watch!
كلا! نسيتُ ساعتي
Say, Mori-san! Would you like to go for a drive?
صحيح، ما رأيك بأن نذهب في نزهة بالسيّارة يا موري-سان؟
I know a place with a beautiful night view!
!أعرف مكاناً بمنظرٍ ليليّ جميل
But it's no fun unless you go with someone else!
لكنّه ليس ممتعاً إذا لم يكن معك أحد
Won't you come with me?
هلّا رافقتني؟
Sounds great! Let's go!
!يبدو ذلك رائعاً! لنذهب
Then I'll pull the car out!
سأخرج السيّارة إذاً
Are you cramped?
أتشعر بضيق؟
You can pull the seat back. There's a lever under the seat.
يمكنك إرجاع الكرسيّ، توجد ذراع رفع تحت المقعد
Thanks...
شكراً
Huh?
ماذا؟
I was working late by myself earlier,
كنتُ أعمل في الشركة بمفردي لوقتٍ متأخّر الليلة
but I came back to check on my roommate, who caught a cold.
لكنّي شعرت بالقلق على زميلتي في الغرفة التي تعاني من زكام، ورجعت للتفقّد عليها
Don't you need to go back to work, then?
أليس عليكِ العودة للشركة إذاً؟
It's alright!
لا داعي
Hearing your exploits as a great detective would be even more useful!
الاستماع لقصص إنجازاتك في التحرّي سيكون مفيداً لعملي أكثر
I'm so glad he had an emergency come up!
!أنا مسرورٌ لأنّه غادر لحالته الطارئة
And the night is still young!
!ولا يزال الليل في مقتبله
Shimamura Sachiko Takenaka Kazumi
شيمامورا ساتشيكو تاكيناكا كازومي
I had so much fun tonight!
استمتعتُ كثيراً الليلة
I had a lot of fun, too!
!وأنا بدوري
Well, good night!
عمتَ مساءً إذاً
Good night!
!عمتِ مساءً
Is something the matter?
أهناك خطبٌ ما؟
The door... It's unlocked...
الباب... ليس مقفلاً
The deceased is Takenaka Kazumi-san, a 29 year-old attendant.
الضحية هي تاكيناكا كازومي-سان، مضيفة في التاسعة والعشرين
Mori-san and her roommate Shimamura Sachiko-san found her.
كان موري-سان وزميلتها في الغرفة شيمامورا ساتشيكو-سان من وجداها
Judging from the rigor mortis of her lower jaw and neck,
،بناءً على تصلّب فكّها السفلي وعنقها
she died approximately two-and-a-half hours ago, around 9:00 pm.
،فقد ماتت قبل ساعتين ونصف من الآن أي عند قرابة التاسعة
Still...
...مع ذلك
Mori-kun! What are those two doing here?!
موري-كن، لمَ هذان الاثنان هنا؟
Sorry about that!
!آسف
I called to let them know, and they came here on their own!
اتّصلت بهما لأخبرهما، لكنّهما أتيا من تلقاء نفسيهما
What was Dad doing in a girl's home?!
لمَ كان أبي في شقّة فتاة؟
This is Sachiko-san's room.
هذه غرفة ساتشيكو-سان
It connects to the victim's room via dining room and kitchen.
إنّها متّصلة بغرفة الضحيّة عبر غرفة طعام ومطبخ
And, as you can see, this window is slightly open.
وكما ترون، هذه النافذة مفتوحة قليلاً
She says she might've forgotten to lock it.
تقول أنّها ربما نسيت إقفالها
Meaning the killer entered through this window?
أي أنّ القاتل دخل عبر هذه النافذة؟
But how would they get onto this veranda?
لكن كيف يستطيع الصعود لشرفة في الطابق الثالث؟
Inspector!
!حضرة المفتّش
Wait! That's dangerous!
!أنت! هذا خطر
See! You can jump onto the veranda from the emergency stairs!
!انظر، يمكنك القفز على الشرفة من سلالم الطوارئ
What do you think you're doing?!
!ما الذي تفعله؟
The intruder probably didn't realize Kazumi-san was sick in bed.
لم ينتبه القاتل لكازومي-سان المريضة على فراشها غالباً
So, during a search for things of value in the kitchen,
،فبينما كان يبحث عن الأشياء القيّمة في المطبخ
the sound woke Kazumi-san,
رأى كازومي-سان التي استيقظت من الجلبة
and the thief stabbed her out of surprise!
!وطعنها في ردّة فعله
And then the intruder escaped through the front door.
ثمّ هرب من الباب الأمامي
In other words, it was a robbery-murder!
أي أنّها كانت جريمة سطو وقتل
It would seem so.
ذلك ما يبدو
I'm sorry to ask, but where were you at around 9:00?
اعذريني على السؤال، لكن أين كنتِ عند التاسعة؟
At that time, I was taking a drive with Mori-san.
في ذاك الوقت، كنتُ أقود في نزهة مع موري-سان
Eh?! With Mori-kun?
ماذا؟ مع موري-كن؟
Y-Yes, well...
...حـ-حسناً
But, Dad! Weren't you meeting a friend tonight?
لكن يا أبي، ألم تكن ستلتقي صديقاً الليلة؟
I did meet him, but something came up so we ended early.
التقيتُه، لكن طرأ أمرٌ عاجل فتعيّن عليه الذهاب
So I returned to Beika Station, strolled around 2nd Street to sober up,
فرجعتُ لمحطّة بيكا ومشيتُ في الشارع الثاني حتّى أصحو
and then ran into Sachiko-san behind Beika Middle School,
ثمّ التقيت بساتشيكو-سان وراء مدرسة بيكا الإعداديّة
as she was getting into her car!
وهي تهمّ بصعود السيّارة
Behind the middle school?
وراء المدرسة الإعداديّة
When was this?
متى كان ذلك؟
Right at 8:00. Then we both went for a drive.
عند الثامنة تقريباً، ذهبنا بعدها في نزهة بالسيّارة
She knew a nice spot with a good view of the Toto Bay Bridge,
كانت تعرف مكاناً ممتازاً بمنظر مطلّ على جسر خليج توتو
and we arrived there at about 8:30.
ووصلنا هناك عند الثامنة والنصف تقريباً
We chatted for about an hour and a half
تحدّثنا بعدها لساعة ونصف
while we drank beer and juice she bought from a vending machine,
بينما نشرب الجعّة والعصير اللذين قامت بشرائهما من آلة البيع
and then left at around 10:10.
وغادرنا عند العاشرة وعشر دقائق
We stopped by her office for about five minutes,
مررنا بمكتبها في طريقنا لخمس دقائق
and then arrived here at about 10:50.
ثمّ وصلنا لمجمع الشقق هذا عند العاشرة والخمسين
That's when we found the body and contacted you.
ووجدنا الجثّة وقمنا بالاتّصال بك
Meaning you're her...
...أي أنّك
Yes! I'm witness to her alibi!
أجل، أنا شاهد حجّة غيابها
Still, what were you doing behind Beika Middle School?
لكن، ما سرّ لقائك بموري-كن وراء مدرسة بيكا الإعداديّة؟
I run a small import company on Akebono Street.
أدير شركة استيراد صغيرة في شارع أكيبونو
I was working late by myself tonight.
كنتُ أعمل لوقتٍ متأخّر بمفردي الليلة
But I was worried about Kazumi, since she was in bed with a cold,
لكنّي شعرت بالقلق على كازومي بما أنّها كانت لزيمة الفراش بالزكام
so I came back to check on her at around 7:50.
فرجعتُ لتفقّدها عند السابعة وخمسين دقيقة تقريباً
Did you see Kazumi-san then?
هل التقيتِ كازومي-سان حينها؟
I didn't really talk to her; she was fast asleep,
التقيتُها؟ كانت تغطّ في النوم
so I left her alone and went straight back to my car.
فلم أرد إيقاظها ورجعتُ لسيّارتي
Say. Why did you park your car behind the middle school?
أخبريني، لمَ ركنتِ سيّارتك وراء المدرسة الإعداديّة؟
Eh?
ماذا؟
Why didn't you use the apartment building's parking lot?
لمَ لم تستعملي ساحة مواقف المبنى
Our parking lot is a two-level, top-bottom type, so it's a pain to use.
ساحة المواقف هنا بطابقين، فمن المتعب استعمالها
And I planned to return to my office right after.
وكنتُ أنوي العودة للشركة فوراً
Then couldn't you park in front of the apartment building?
كان بإمكانك ركن السيّارة أمام المبنى إذاً
I would have gotten in the way of the buses that pass by the front.
كنتُ لأعترض طريق الحافلات التي تمرّ أمامه
"To Shimamura Sachiko"...
"إلى شيمامورا ساتشيكو-ساما"
This is addressed to you.
هذا موجّه لك
When did this package arrive?
متى وصل هذا الطرد؟
I don't know...
...لا أدري
Was it here when you came to check on Kazumi-san?
أكان هنا عندما أتيتِ لتفقّد كازومي-سان؟
No, I don't remember.
لا، لا أتذكّر
Understood. We'll check with the delivery people tomorrow.
حسنٌ، سنتفقّد مع شركة التوصيل غداً
Something really bothers me...
هناك ما يضايقني
Huh? The fish bones?
ماذا؟ عظام السمكة؟
Not that. The reason Sachiko-san parked her car behind Beika Middle School.
كلا، سبب ركن ساتشيكو-سان لسيّارتها وراء مدرسة بيكا الإعداديّة
Say, Dad.
أخبرني يا أبي
What did you talk about for an hour and a half
عمّا تكلّمت عند نقطة إطلالة جسر الخليج
at the Bay Bridge view point?!
لساعة ونصف؟
And why did you go on a drive with her, anyway?!
ولمَ ذهبت في نزهة بالسيّارة معها بالأصل؟
Dad! Don't tell me you two--
...أيمكن أنّك يا أبي
W-What are you trying to say?! I didn't do anything improper!
!ما-ما الذي تلمّحين له؟! لم أقم بأيّ شيءٍ شائن
Then tell me what you talked about!
!أخبرني عمَّ تكلّمتما إذاً
I don't remember everything we said! Besides, halfway through--
...لا أتذكّر كلّ شيءٍ قلناه! كما أنّي في المنتصف
Halfway through... what?!
في المنتصف... ماذا؟
No, uhh...
...لا
Dad!
!أبي
The truth is, we only chatted for the first half hour.
في الواقع، تكلّمنا لأوّل 30 دقيقة فقط
I fell deep asleep after that.
ونمتُ بعمقٍ بعدها
You fell asleep?
نمت؟
Yeah. Drunkenness started to set in while I had those beers.
أجل، غلبتني الثمالة بينما أشرب الجعّة
It was after 10:00 when she woke me up.
وعندما أيقظتني، كانت الساعة قد تجاوزت العاشرة بقليل
That's so funny! You fell asleep during a date!
!طريف! نمت أثناء موعد
Quit laughing! Sheesh!
...لا تضحكي! يا إلهي
That's why I didn't want to say anything!
!لذا لم أرد قول شيء
He fell asleep halfway through?
نام أثناء ذلك؟
But he was awake until 9:00, chatting with her.
لكنّه كان مستيقظاً حتّى التاسعة يحادثها
The murder took place around 9:00. Her alibi is airtight.
وقعت الجريمة حول التاسعة، حجّة غيابها متينة
Wait a minute!
!انتظر
Hey. You forgot your watch yesterday, right?
نسيتَ ساعة معصمك البارحة، صحيح يا عمّ؟
How did you know the time?
كيف عرفتَ الوقت؟
I saw the clock in the car.
رأيتُ الساعة في السيّارة
What about before then?
وقبل صعودك لها؟
There was a clock in the bar, and I saw a clock at Shibahama Station.
،كانت هناك ساعة في الحانة ورأيتُ الساعة في محطّة شيباهاما
What time was it?!
!ما كان الوقت؟
7:30.
السابعة والنصف
7:30?
السابعة والنصف؟
It's fifteen minutes from Shibahama Station to Beika Station.
،تحتاج 15 دقيقة من محطّة شيباهاما إلى محطّة بيكا
It's ten minutes by foot from Beika Station to Beika Middle School.
وعشر دقائق مشياً من محطّة بيكا لمدرسة بيكا الإعداديّة
Which means you ran into Sachiko-san at around...
...أي أنّك التقيتَ ساتشيكو-سان عند
I already told you! 8:00 exactly!
!أخبرتُك عند الثامنة
I heard the clock in a nearby house ring!
!سمعتُ جرس ساعة في منزلٍ قريب
Now eat your damn food and go to school!
!فلتأكل طعامك وتذهب للمدرسة وحسب
Okay!
!حسناً
He's right. I should just forget about it.
إنّه محق، عليّ نسيان الأمر فقط
Three laps around the schoolyard is really exhausting!
!ثلاث لفّات حول فناء المدرسة أمرٌ مرهق
I can't go on...
...لا أستطيع الاستمرار
Just a little more! Hang in there, Genta!
!بقي القليل! تماسك يا غينتا
Hey! Thinking about something you like makes it go quicker!
اسمع، التفكّير بأمرٍ تحبّه يجعل الوقت يمضي أسرع
Something I like?
أمر أحبّه؟
Alright! I'm gonna have boxed eel lunch tonight!
!حسنٌ! سآكل علبة غداء أنقليس الليلة
Boxed eel lunch! Boxed eel lunch! Tonight--
...علبة غداء أنقليس! علبة غداء أنقليس! الليلة
Wait, Genta! We're done now!
!غينتا! لقد انتهينا
Oh no. He's too busy thinking about boxed eel lunches.
كلا، إنّه منهمكٌ في التفكير بعلبة غداء الأنقليس
I bet he's going to do another lap!
لا بدّ أنّه سيقوم بلفّةٍ أخرى
Could it be?!
...أيمكن
One trip around the Loop Line?!
!دورة كاملة على خطّ الحلقة؟
Could you have fallen asleep after you got on at Shibahama Station?
أيمكن أنّك غططت في النوم بعدما صعدت القطار في محطّة شيباهاما؟
A trip around the Loop Line takes an hour!
تستغرق الدورة الكاملة على خطّ الحلقة ساعةً واحدة
If you had gone around it once while you were asleep,
،إذا أتممتها بينما كنتَ نائماً
you would've reached Beika Station at 8:40 instead of 7:40!
فقد وصلتَ محطّة بيكا عند الثامنة وأربعين دقيقة، وليس السابعة وأربعون
Nonsense! I only slept for fifteen minutes! I couldn't have looped around!
!هراء! نمت لخمس عشرة دقيقة فحسب !يستحيل أنّني أتممت دورة
Then let's see for ourselves!
لنتحقّق بأنفسنا إذاً
What?
ماذا؟
Let's all ride the Loop Line tonight!
!لنصعد خطّ الحلقة جميعاً الليلة
In the same train and train car leaving Shibahama Station at 7:30!
نفس القطار ونفس العربة المغادران !لمحطّة شيباهاما عند السابعة والنصف
I guess that'll be fine...
لا أمانع ذلك
Well, Dad? Remember anything?
إذاً يا أبي؟ أتذكّرت شيئاً؟
No, I guess I was pretty out of it.
كلا، يبدو أنّي كنت غائب العقل تماماً
But she can't be the killer!
!لكن لا يمكن أنّها القاتلة
Let's just take a full trip around. Okay?
لنكمل الدورة بأيّ حال، حسناً؟
This is the furthest stop from Shibahama Station.
هذه أبعد محطّة من محطّة شيباهاما، صحيح؟
What is it? Do you know that man?
ما الأمر؟ أتعرفون هذا الرجل؟
Candy!
!حلوى
He was sleeping with his mouth wide open yesterday...
...كان هذا الرجل نائماً وفمه مفتوحاً بالأمس
...so he tossed a piece of candy in there!
!فرمى هذا قطعة حلوى داخله
What time was that?!
متى كان ذلك؟
The same as today. Around 8:00.
مثل اليوم، عند الثامنة
Which means I arrived at Beika Station just before 9:00!
!ما يعني أنّي وصلت محطّة بيكا قبيل التاسعة
And that I ran into Sachiko-san at 9:00!
!ووقت لقائي بساتشيكو-سان كان التاسعة
Yes! You arrived at the Toto Bay Bridge view point at 9:30!
أجل! وصلتِ نقطة إطلالة جسر !خليج توتو عند التاسعة والنصف
Then you chatted for thirty minutes, until 10:00!
!ثمّ تحادثتما لثلاثين دقيقة حتّى العاشرة
And then you woke up at 10:10!
!وأيقظتك عند العاشرة وعشر دقائق
You were wrong about sleeping for an hour and ten minutes!
أخطأتَ في اعتقادك أنّك ،كنت نائماً لساعة وعشر دقائق
You only slept for ten minutes!
!بل نمت لعشر دقائق فحسب
In other words, she turned the clock back an hour
أي أنّها أعادت الساعة ساعةً واحدة
to use me for her alibi...
لتجعلني أشهد على حجّة غيابها
Last night, she parked her car in this out-of-the-way location
البارحة، ركنت سيّارتها في هذا المكان المخفيّ عن الأنظار
and left to kill the victim.
وذهبت لقتل الضحيّة
She entered through the window she had unlocked in advance,
دخلت غرفتها من النافذة التي تركتها مفتوحة سلفاً
made sound on purpose,
وأصدرت صوتاً مُتعمِّدة
then killed the awoken victim to make it look like a robbery-murder.
وقتلت الضحيّة التي استيقظت لتجعلها تبدو جريمة سطو وقتل
After that, she returned here and ran into you.
بعدها، رجعت إلى هنا والتقتك، صحيح؟
Come to think of it, she...
...بالمناسبة، كان معها وقتها
Were they the bloodied clothes and gloves she used in the murder?!
أكانت تلك الثياب المغطّاة بالدماء والقفّازات التي استعملتها في الجريمة؟
If so, then she disposed of them at the view point while you slept.
في تلك الحالة، لا بدّ أنّها تخلصت منهما عند نقطة الإطلالة بينما كنت نائماً
She set the car clock an hour ahead before you got in.
قدّمت ساعة السيّارة بساعة واحدة قبل صعودك
Then, while you were asleep, she put it back to normal.
ثمّ أعادتها لطبيعتها بعدما كنت نائماً
Damn it! How dare she toy with the great Mori Kogoro?!
!اللعنة! كيف تجرؤ على التلاعب بالمتحرّي العظيم موري كوغورو؟
Was there anything else out of the ordinary?
أكان هناك شيءٌ آخر خارج المألوف؟
The children saw Mori-san?
رأى الأطفالُ موري-سان؟
Your alibi no longer holds.
انهارت حجّة غيابك
You met Mori-kun behind Beika Middle School just after the crime.
التقيتِ موري-كن وراء مدرسة بيكا الإعداديّة بعد وقوع الجريمة
But isn't it possible the children mistook Mori-san
لكن ألا يُحتمل أنّ الأطفال خلطوا بين موري-سان
for someone else who looks similar?
وشخص آخر يشبهه؟
That possibility does exist.
...ذلك مُحتمل
Even if by some chance my alibi doesn't check out,
،حتّى لو لم تكن حجّة غيابي تامّة
that doesn't mean that I killed Kazumi-san.
فذلك لا يعني قتلي لكازومي
Yes, that's correct. But there is proof!
!كلامكِ صحيح، لكن يوجد دليل
I leave it in your hands today, old guy!
أترك الأمر لك اليوم يا عمّ
Do you recognize this pen?
أتذكرين قلم الحبر الجافّ هذا؟
Yes. It's your pen, isn't it?
!أجل، إنّه قلمك، أليس كذلك؟
Dad!
!أبي
Are you alright, Mori-kun?!
!أأنت بخير يا موري-كن؟
Oh, geez! Do I have to do it after all?!
!يا إلهي! أعليّ فعلها في النهاية؟
Let us go back to 8:30 pm two nights ago.
لنرجع للثامنة والنصف قبل ليلتين
A deliveryman knocked on the door, and Kazumi-san answered it.
،وصل رجل شركة شحن لتوصيل طرد وخرجت كازومي-سان له
However, she couldn't find her ink stamp.
لكنّها لم تجد ختمها الحبريّ
With no other choice,
،لم يكن أمامها خيارٌ آخر
she decided to sign for it with a pen in the dining room.
فوقّعت بقلم الحبر الجاف الذي كان في غرفة الطعام
But it wouldn't write.
لكنّه لم يكتب
Supposedly, the deliveryman said it might be the ink,
وفقما يبدو، فقد شكّ رجل التوصيل بكون المشكلة في الحبر
so he took the pen and looked inside.
فأخرج القلم وتفقّده
Some ink was still left, and when she tried to write again, it worked.
كان لا يزال هناك بعض الحبر، فحاولت كازومي-سان الكتابة مجدداً، ونجحت
When the deliveryman left, Kazumi-san placed the pen by the phone
عندما غادر رجل التوصيل، وضعت كازومي-سان القلم بجوار الهاتف في غرفة الطعام
and returned to her room to sleep.
ورجعت للنوم في غرفتها مجدداً
Twenty minutes later...
...وبعد عشرين دقيقة
Seeing your own pen lying next to her body
بعد رؤيتكِ لقلمك الذي سقط بجوار الجثّة
right after you killed her, you instinctually picked it up and...
...حملتِه غريزياً لكونكِ المجرمة، ثمّ
Afterward, you invited me for a drive
بعدها، قمتِ بدعوتي لنزهةٍ بالسيّارة
and moved the clothes and gloves under the passenger seat
ونقلتِ الملابس والقفّازات تحت مقعد الراكب الأمامي
to under the back seat.
لأسفل المقاعد الخلفيّة
When you did, the pen in your pocket fell out.
عندها، سقط قلم الحبر السائل الذي وضعتِه في جيبك
You didn't seem to notice, but after I got into the passenger seat,
يبدو أنّك لم تلحظي، لكن بعدما جلست ،في مقعد الراكب الأمامي
I dropped a pen from my suit, too.
أسقطتُ قلمي من بدلتي بدوري
I assume you can guess what happened next.
يمكنكِ فهم ما حصل الآن
What I picked up was your pen instead of mine!
ما حملتُه كان قلمك الذي ظننتُ أنّه يخصّني
We found the fingerprints of you and Mori-kun on this pen.
وجدنا بصماتك وبصمات كازومي-سان كما بصمات موري-كن على هذا القلم
In addition, the fingerprints of the deliveryman were on the ink stick.
إضافةً لذلك، كانت بصمات رجل التوصيل على عصا الحبر
These fingerprints mean you entered the apartment after 8:30!
هذه البصمات دليلٌ على دخولكِ الشقّة !بعد الثامنة والنصف
Isn't that right?
ألستُ محقّاً؟
Kazumi was blackmailing me!
!كانت كازومي تبتزّني
One year ago, I unknowingly imported and sold outlawed goods.
قبل عام، استوردتُ وبعت بضائع محظورة في جهلي
Kazumi knew this, and demanded I pay her a set amount each month.
عرفت كازومي ذلك، وطلبت منّي دفع مبلغ محدّد شهرياً
She threatened to tell the banks and cut off my financing if I said no,
هدّدت بإخبار المصرف وقطع التمويل الذي أحتاجه إذا رفضت
so I did as she said.
فلم يكن أمامي سوى الخضوع لها
But when I considered being blackmailed for the rest of my life...
...لكن عندما فكّرتُ بابتزازها لي لبقيّة حياتي
You decided to kill her at once.
قرّرتِ قتلها
Yes.
أجل
When Mori-san called out to me, I thought I was already done for.
،عندما ناداني موري-سان في الواقع ظننتُ أنّ أمري انتهى
But I realized he thought it was an hour earlier than it really was
لكنّي أدركتُ أنّه متأخّر في حسابه للوقت بساعة
and decided to use that to my advantage.
فقرّرتُ استغلال ذلك لمصلحتي
But what did you plan to do for an alibi if he hadn't shown up?
لكن كيف نويتِ صنع حجّة غيابٍ لك في حال لم يظهر موري-كن؟
I set a video camera in my office window
وضعتُ كاميرا فيديو موجّهة من نافذة مكتبي
and recorded the pub across the street.
وصوّرتُ تسجيلاً للحانة على الشارع المقابل
I planned to tell the police it was one of the customers leaving
خطّطتُ لإخبار الشرطة أنّه كان أحد الزبائن المغادرين
at the time of the crime.
وقت وقوع الجريمة
So you stopped by your office after your drive with Mori-kun
مررتِ بمكتبك بعد جولتك مع موري-كن
to take down that video camera?
كي تزيلي كاميرا الفيديو تلك، صحيح؟
Yes. The rest is all as Mori-san deduced.
أجل، الباقي كما استنتج موري-سان
I'm sorry for all the trouble.
أعتذر على المتاعب التي تسبّبتُ بها
Say. Can I ask you one thing?
أيمكنني سؤالك عن شيء؟
Conan-kun!
!كونان-كن
But you didn't. How come?
لكنّك لم تفعلي ذلك، فلمَ؟
I don't hold anything against Mori-san, after all.
لم أكن أكنّ أيّ ضغينة تّجاه موري-سان
This face... I've seen it somewhere long ago...
هذا الوجه... رأيتُه في مكانٍ ما في الماضي
Come to think of it, you're always wearing glasses, Conan-kun.
بالمناسبة، أنت ترتدي النظّارات دوماً يا كونان-كن
Even when sleeping or taking a bath. Why?
حتّى عند النوم وعند الاستحمام، لمَ؟
I-I can't relax without them on.
لا-لا أستطيع الاسترخاء دونها
On the next Conan Special!
المتحرّي العظيم محاصَر! جريمتا قتل كبيرتان توالياً
Next Conan's hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Actress.
ممثلة مشهورة
Next episode is our first two-hour special.
!الحلقة القادمة أوّل حلقة خاصّة من ساعتين
See if you can handle it.
!حاولوا حلّ اللغزين